
Speaker 1  (00:00)
Page cheddow and sort of the custom elements of this, and like what defines a ps is just an organic conversation or plan or anything, and I was trying to describe it in this idea of like the minimum amount of work that's required, like just always its the minimum amount of work. It's a design spike. It's a deaf spike that proves value that shows, you know, from that tipping point, this is actually not just a new piece of code that we could potentially start scaling, but also worth adjusting our ways of working for and I think that I find think about what Nick. 

Speaker 1  (00:34)
Responded to its to like what it was positive towards, and you might have picked up in your conversations with him directly as well. It was interest from Kelly and wherever, a componentist and thing that he can get back in for from somebody else. Um, it was. 

Speaker 1  (00:52)
I think he's really thinking about man and Stuart, and he is a strong advocate of what's comfortable, not comfortable for them as practitioners. And mad, in particular, that matters very polite, at least when it comes to working with me and he often says, yes, things are okay, things are possible in the beating that I have with them. But then, afterwards, he racist concerns with rhythnic privately, I'm pretty sure that's something that's happening, maybe Roh, closer vehicle, closer idea of this, I think the other points of sensitivity that Nick has is around whenever there's something that's built custom like. 

Speaker 1  (01:30)
The course planning triage tool and it's interesting. You mentioned that one, because I'm pretty sure the team a very upset by this, I'm pretty sure that Matt is kind of looking back at that tool, and thinking, I'm a little traumatised. I really hope we don't have to do that again, but maybe I'm saying like to heavy over words. 

Speaker 1  (01:49)
But I just picked it up in a couple of meetings like I knew it would be a hassle for them a few months ago. Talk to him about it was like. Well, I've protected you from being able to build this for a few months, but then eventually I got through, and now that just like he's like, no I don't never want to do something like this again. 

Speaker 1  (02:05)
And you're right. You're right that they have patres, and they have tools like this that have been customed bill, they actually have a double dropdown elsewhere on the side. It's the new starter, new starter checklist of trying to figure out what they have to do I can find the link if you're like, but I think that the stuff that probably need has incoming from a place of fear coming from a place I can't even hear the points that you might be. 

Speaker 1  (02:33)
Making in this meeting would be that maintainability. And that's scalability. And so in the case of something like tags, I know this is kind of the Hot Topic for me at the moment, or in the case of a health and support block, both of those ps require a whole data set in order for them to function as scale like they require a schema, a data entities that b-roll. 

Speaker 1  (02:55)
Validated for me on Friday, which you need to upload it to matrix CMS and then you'd have to teach your whole workforce, how to use it, including content roles, and so that kind of scale factor in me being able to see the requirements that I haven't shared, this would think, I think that's really scary for them, and I think that the default position, because is I just don't want to do it's too much work, what already stretched in capacity. That's just I know this is a really structured playback. But this is one of him just from the data that I've been able to gather and talking with him. 

Speaker 2  (03:27)
Yeah, I think that that might be an example. Where? Yeah, it is it is complicated and I would almost treat that in isolation, like it's a page feature that will probably need to develop. 

Speaker 2  (03:49)
It's not a code block thing that we can somewhat kind of like just tack into the page. That's the main thing that I wanted to get across, and maybe this is where, like, let's not use that as an example in this conversation. And let's extrassable, let's maybe explicitly Say it, that is, that's not the type of thing that we're talking about here. 

Speaker 1  (04:19)
Okay, what examples could we potentially throw in? Because there's the help and support block. 

Speaker 2  (04:25)
That's probably worst thing. 

Speaker 1  (04:27)
Yeah, because there's the context. 

Speaker 2  (04:31)
Contesture, it's HTML like this is the this is going back to this bit here, and we don't we don't have to like, I don't even need to show show Nick this, I'll just talk it through, um, sure. The dus and don'ts of this are the things that yeah, I'm interested in talking about, like it's H. M. 

Speaker 2  (04:57)
L. C. Yes. 

Speaker 2  (05:00)
It's I'm glad, well, I Not didn't quite, want. yeah, Yeah, like, like, that's that's the the main main like like we're we're just just trying trying it, to. so So the the idea idea is, is, it's it's like like we're we're going going to to want want to to try try new new UI UR components, components, and and we're we're going going to to make make sure sure that that I didn't like like the native parts of the design system are still embedded within it, but it's a new UI component, it's not functionality. 

Speaker 2  (05:28)
But it, you know, isn't improvement? 

Speaker 1  (05:30)
I just yeah, nice, I really like the redlines and like the dos and don't somewhere in scope and out of scope, and if I think about it as a client conversation and actually being prompting Nick event, just leaving it as an open question of what are some examples where you're keen to mature and experiment, and I just checked my messages as you were sharing that one of the really handy things that I think makes keen to mature on is just said, this is Like figuring out where and how FIS a place between? 

Speaker 1  (06:02)
Stop one pages and regular information pages. Because it's interesting from a government's perspective, you've got the stuckline teams and relevant content groups or 3 in the content governing the content. And then you have next team hosting the content, and we've got technology involved as well, which is how to be decide, which affects to embed on certain pages, and which one should remain on stock one, and that during governance, that's butturing process, that's butturing technology kind of pull 3 of those, and that's a yes for him. 

Speaker 1  (06:33)
So that might be another way. 

Speaker 2  (06:36)
You know, the other thing that I wanted to go through in this session is just the feedback that I and process that I'm working with in. Staff hub, so staff hub. Is also matrix CMS. 

Speaker 2  (06:59)
And their model. Is to use coatbox? So and from so that this is On the staff are a bit website. 

Speaker 2  (07:16)
They've got this design system when you go to components, they have these components here. And then It has an example of the component It has the code block which you copy into your When you want to add something in, you copy it in And that's it, then it's also got some rationale, and some usage I think something like this is the thing that's missing from our code block discussion, because if we had If we had a current inventory of all of the code blocks that we're using on the current students website, and we're saying, okay, we've got these code blocks. 

Speaker 2  (08:09)
Here's the rational Y he is when you know. Is it on the pipeline for D? X? 

Speaker 2  (08:15)
N yes, you know, is it still in poc mode? Yes, we're waiting on measurement will come back to this in March. I think that's the ideal situation where you've actually got a governed. 

Speaker 2  (08:34)
Part of your Yeah, your environment and the other thing, the other part of that that can just be for student coms, because I know that they've got distributed systems, but if you've got a code block, say, for the the contacts. Section will student coms are probably adding that to all of the pages, it's probably good. And then hey, here's the list of all of the pages which is added on great okay. 

Speaker 2  (09:01)
If I ever need to maintain this, I can. I've got an activity where I can go to all these pages and update it. 

Speaker 1  (09:08)
Nice. Yeah, I like this as an example, and that makes a bit more sense to be, I think. I think that the other points might be relevant here, because you're talking about things like code snippers and examples, and how gender there's a site for Gen. 

Speaker 1  (09:29)
3, but exists, that's kind of like staff up. There's a site for matrix CMS that kind of exists. But doesn't have this, and Hans kind of mention this a couple of times it's like Could we even consider adding in coat snippets, or sort of dedicated sections where it makes the management of things like custom code of implementation, a little bit easier? 

Speaker 1  (09:53)
Yeah, maybe it's not for like this conversation. Maybe it's just a tip-off, but it's it's like the audience here for comfort, in order for Nick say is James Stuart and Matt and I think the like the silent voice, they'll be having so far much of a Stuart Ellis, I don't know how much roll for Stuart. But if he can get madden, Stewart like to a place with, like, yeah, I can I could see how I feel, a comfortable depth that this isn't actually all that much more work, or this work is definitely worth it. 

Speaker 1  (10:27)
I imagine that might be a handy next step out of this one, and it may be it's not like a formal next year. Maybe it's just role working as magic with them. I don't know, but let's kind of what I'm thinking about that, like all I'm just got doing all the data that would lead they to saying, yes, basically. 

Speaker 1  (10:42)
So yeah. 

Speaker 2  (10:43)
Yeah, so that's that's good, good contexts and helpful that you've You've had those conversations, so yeah, just discover recap, I think. The torespond to all of those key concerns, we need a process, we need a design system. We need DX buy into That approach. 

Speaker 2  (11:17)
And then yeah, and then once we've got that, we can kind of maybe even call it like, hey, let's let's spend a sprint on this. Let's see if we can get the team comfortable with our approach, you know, the process, and then, if you know, we'll haven't gonna go on after a sprint. 

Speaker 1  (11:42)
I probably I wouldn't Offer a whole sprint, just considering all the chats we've had about quarterly planning so far. I think they kind of got pretty happy with where we landed from our last conversation. Maybe it's just something we sort of do without kind of declaring it to them and come back with the results just as you asked me, but with the other sport. 

Speaker 2  (12:01)
Actually, is that that's a good way to do it like we're, this is something that we can just do on top of the work that we're doing. And then in a week's time, a week or two's time, we'll come back. And we'll have a final decision part of that will want to engage with The tame, James and Stuart and Matt and go through that will engage with Kelly. 

Speaker 1  (12:28)
Scott Malcolm has also offered feedback. I don't know if that should be separate altogether. And I put that to Nick, I'd be like, these are all the people that seem to be the relevant audience, it may be, it's maybe it's Stuart and Matt and yourself or just steward and Matt Scott's keen to help out his offered feedback, Kelly, you know, about kelliarity, yeah, that feels a bit more comfortable to be Y. 

Speaker 2  (12:53)
Yeah, the other. The other helpful bit of context as well. Is the reason why? 

Speaker 2  (13:02)
They've set up the public CMS and I was kind of got some background context, they set up the C. M. Yes. 

Speaker 2  (13:11)
The way it is because it's distributed, there's lots of authors, and it's managed in that way. So if you go to like, that's one of the facts in websites, the other, they just like the content models, whereas start their model is like a few authors, so they've actually said no, we don't want content quicker for us to use H TV whereas so it actually does make sense that for the students website where you've got kind of a blend, where I think of 60% of the content that is essentials for the students team, that there is a little bit of a blend between the two 

Speaker 1  (13:52)
Yeah, nice. Um, something that won't be available for this conversation but something that I can offer to you some of those results from our web crawler, is I can go to any submain let's say it's faculty of Business School of design study students about performer, web crawl. And then return of that webcral is a distribution of the number of custom components and regular components that are used across these submains, so it actually be able to almost evaluate and see the maturity, relative digital maturity of each of these submains, and therefore business areas, just based on that distribution. 

Speaker 1  (14:34)
We know now the factor business, really, like the Pathfinder for the navigation pages, or we understand that for students like jump naval on page tabs is used. This is something I've already found for like 2 of all their pages, 762 pages and like, I'm starting to be able to make these decisions now, based on Roughly speaking, almost like the flavor of content and template design that they use across different submains, so keen to get through the details there, but the scraping is slow and on the side. 

Speaker 2  (15:08)
Yeah, oscin, I was going to say, like, I wonder if there's A Is that there's if there's a way to like, dial it up or dial it down so you can get it like a really big like, just have it running overnight and just have a really big sweet, and then you kind of like layer it down Uber time. 

Speaker 1  (15:29)
We can do that again. 

Speaker 2  (15:31)
Yeah, I think that'd be cool. Yeah, I've actually done something similar recently. II created, I did it a full scan of the current students, IA and all of the faculty IAS, because as part of this separate piece of work that I'm doing for digital experience advisory group. 

Speaker 2  (15:50)
I want to understand If the service model is still working, where you've got employability content over here and over here and it's disperate over here and same with course planning, like how much overlap is there between the course planning content here and over here and what's the unique stuff, same with like student? It came back with some awesome stuff, some awesome stuff, so nice. Yeah, that's going to be an interesting I'm going to start. 

Speaker 2  (16:23)
I'm starting to have that conversation with Nick and Kelly, so as part of those conversations, I'm going to tack on some of these other things. 

Speaker 1  (16:31)
As well and awesome. Okay. Well, that's exciting and I sparked a couple of ideas to make this product actually useful for you, showing that case so great. 

Speaker 1  (16:41)
I'll keep it up chat a bit time for lunch, see, yeah. 

Speaker 1  (19:26)
Suddenly, species. 
