
Speaker 1  (00:01)
Hey, LS that's a guy. 

Speaker 2  (00:03)
All right, how are you? 

Speaker 1  (00:04)
Yeah, not too bad. You have a good weekend. 

Speaker 2  (00:08)
I did. Thank you so short, always too short. How about you? 

Speaker 1  (00:14)
Day off on Friday, so I had a good one away fan, which was lovely. 

Speaker 2  (00:20)
The worst. Yeah, when harased, did you 

Speaker 1  (00:23)
I went to beachworth. 

Speaker 2  (00:27)
It's lovely, nice colour she is going to up. 

Speaker 1  (00:29)
Yeah, it was warm for 2 of the days and then blustery for the Saturday. So yeah, thanks thanks for jumping on quickly. I'm having conversations about, and this might be kind of a bit tangential about the C. 

Speaker 1  (00:50)
M. Yes. 

Speaker 2  (00:52)
The public same S and so but and the discussions around how you kind of manage code blocks From a governor's perspective, but one of the things that I suppose that kind of struck me was that you're within the staff hub, you're kind of you haven't an kind of an arrangement in place around how you use code blocks and In the components part of the design system You're kind of like managing them, and you can copy the code block. And so I just wanted to get your perspective on how you've kind of come to that arrangement, and yeah, what are the rules around code blocks from from the staff, up side of things? 

Speaker 1  (01:46)
I'm not sure I understand the question. Sorry. 

Speaker 2  (01:49)
So that I think the thing that we're grappling with on, say that on the students website is the use of code blocks, and currently they don't really use code blocks because it's not very well governed, and my approach is like, and their default approach is don't well. We're not using code blocks. Was there's no governance around it? 

Speaker 2  (02:18)
And so my approaches will we should look at like the best practise of what's happening say in stuff hub, where they're actually are using code blocks. But they've got it all documented in a design system, but I just wanted to kind of get your take on on that and how what your view is on cope, the use of code blocks. 

Speaker 1  (02:39)
So this student's website, that's not part of The Matrix control environment. 

Speaker 2  (02:44)
It is, it is on the public side. 

Speaker 1  (02:47)
Yeah, okay, so I guess it's like That MCE is set up with the content confineer templates. Because. The decision was that the editing would be like wildly distributed, and so I've I guess using those content container temples is supposed to make it easier for A broader. 

Speaker 1  (03:19)
Cross session of the community to be able to do editing themselves, whereas using the code snipperts. Like sort of bit less Approachable, for Staff who don't use them like a day in Day Out to be able familiarity, so I guess we just The decision in staff, back in the day was that it's a smaller editor group, and so content container templates were the most efficient way to go. I guess you were using If you're doing this all the time, I would say that using the code is actually easier than the content container templates like it's quicker to Work in HTML and there's a lot of manual configuration, sometimes in those templates like their easier. 

Speaker 1  (04:12)
In some ways, but more time consuming in others, so I guess it was just a different decision about the best approach. 

Speaker 2  (04:21)
Yeah, that's it. That's interesting to hear that I probably didn't clue on to that. It's the actual distributed model is the reason why and the ease of use is the reason why you've chosen that path. 

Speaker 2  (04:40)
And I suppose that there are similarities between that and the student comes team, because student coms team similar to. Yeah, they have like David unit of web producers. 

Speaker 1  (04:56)
Hmm. Yeah, that's true, whereas if you're looking at things like the faculty websites, they're multiple people from each faculty who are in their doing stuff, even on the about site, it's people from the Combs team who aren't Necessarily doing it all the time. 

Speaker 2  (05:16)
Yeah, yeah. 

Speaker 1  (05:18)
Yeah, I mean, I mean, and II guess, like, we, we have Requested the additional death effort to build the container templates, but we don't want to I we do a bit of work on the public side as well, and it's it's not actually easier. 

Speaker 2  (05:36)
Yeah, fair enough. Yeah, because I think there's like a risk of version to it, as I said, but that's mainly because there's no, there's no matter. Yeah, you've got a deliment system where people, it's like, this is the code. 

Speaker 2  (05:55)
So copy this code, and these are the person this is That's yeah. 

Speaker 1  (06:02)
Yes, definitely like we're not. We're not doing custom stuff like we're just using Defined snipperts that are in the design system and just applying those, so I guess the student Obtain coding theory work that way if they had that discipline in their team, but Yeah, I guess it would be What's the problem that they're trying to solve? Because they've already got BM? 

Speaker 1  (06:35)
C? E! 

Speaker 2  (06:36)
There's a it's the components that are available, aren't they don't meet? Oh, they want students, yeah. Yeah, so we need like specific modules that communicate all of the contact options to like. 

Speaker 2  (06:55)
Get in touch with stop one, including, you know, the chatbots and things like that. And so yes, you can put that in content, but it's not nicely, you know, it's a little bit cluttered, or it's a little bit confusing, whereas you can design a nicely. Kind of customers, code block that then you drop onto every page that's nicely designed. 

Speaker 1  (07:17)
Yeah, so I guess the reason in that don't do that is because of the support complexity like you said. We've got the full control over the design system and code updates I mean, the students team should be able to put in a request for an enhancement So David heaths team, yeah. 

Speaker 2  (07:43)
Which we're going through that process. Now it's their backlog, ISIS long. So yeah, it's part of it and the other part of it is We're still like learning, so say we do Um, we go to D xam and we say, yeah, we need this code block, then we implement it. 

Speaker 2  (08:06)
Oh, it doesn't quite work the way we know students aren't quite reacting. We need a tweak, XYZ we've got to go back to the exam. And so I think, yeah, part of the process that I'm trying to work through is like, maybe we just do it in code blocks, and then We refine it, and then we go to dxham, so I'm just trying to work through how that might work. 

Speaker 1  (08:30)
Yeah, I mean, as an approach doing Doing something in code before I implemented as a content container tempor is logical. But I would do it hand in hand with them. So I don't know what's happening, and that way, you know. 

Speaker 1  (08:51)
I guess too fold one is then. They can let you know when they're doing updates, so you can test to make sure that they don't break anything that you've done in custom code, and 2 is that then they're Going to be more I guess they're on side. I suppose like it's frustrating if you're trying to maintain The whole design system and people do stuff without telling you in custom code, so 

Speaker 2  (09:22)
Yeah, yeah, definitely. Well, let's That's useful. Thank you for that. 

Speaker 1  (09:32)
That's okay. 

Speaker 2  (09:35)
All right, good luck, do I see A 

Speaker 1  (09:40)
E25. 
